Guide to the Civic Club of Allegheny County Records, 1896-1974 AIS.1970.02
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Civic Club of Allegheny County Records
1896-1974
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Civic Club of Allegheny County (Pa.)
AIS.1970.02
30.09 Linear Feet (41 boxes)
The mission of the Civic Club of Allegheny County has been "to promote by education and organized non-partisan effort a higher public spirit and better social order." This collection contains the Civic Club by-laws and constitution; minutes of annual board of directors and committee meetings; records documenting the Civic Club's legislative campaigns and social services; Exceptionally Able Youth testing information and program evaluations; and voter directories for general and primary elections between 1930 and 1973.
History
The history of the Civic Club began in 1890, when a group of Pittsburgh women came together to form the Women's Health Protective Association to encourage the development and growth of the city's public health works and charities. By 1895, the association was recommended to become a civic club with "the men [providing] the experience" and "the women the enthusiasm." John A. Brashear took a leadership role in the club by incorporating and chartering it in 1896.
The Civic Club's mission has been "to promote by education and organized non-partisan effort a higher public spirit and better social order." Interested in beautifying the community, providing public services to the working classes, and promoting patriotic and civic-minded education to the city's immigrant populations, this club embodied the progressive ideals of the early twentieth century and continued to promote social consciousness well into the post WWII era.
The accomplishments of the Civic Club included the establishment of city playgrounds, smoke abatement regulations, education programs of workers and immigrants, public baths and laundry in the Soho neighborhood, child labor regulations, contagious disease hospitals, public concerts, and the maintenance of public gardens. The Civic Club played a prominent role in passing legislation for improving the living standards of the city's residents. Some of the Civic Club's legislative causes included pure water acts, garbage collection, school inspections, free bridges, and an improved city charter. One of the Civic Club's most notable contributions was encouraging voter participation. The Civic Club published a voter directory for each primary and general election listing all candidates, their biographies, and qualifications in order to enable citizens to vote intelligently. Another noteworthy club venture, the Exceptionally Able Youth program, provided recognition and motivation to the talented students of Allegheny County from 1916 to 1974.
Due to difficulty obtaining the yearly finances needed to operate the organization, the Civic Club surrendered its charter in 1974 and dissolved.
Scope and Content Notes
The initial records of the Civic Club of Allegheny County are found in Boxes 1-27. These records contain information about the history of the organization, annual meetings from 1896 to 1964, various programs and club activities, and committee work. Subject files about various organizations, social movements, institutions, and activities relating to the Civic Club mission as well as individual files about notable club members are also included. Topics of special interest include child labor legislation, the creation of public comfort stations, the establishment of the Stephen F. Foster Memorial, the maintenance of Pittsburgh playgrounds, Americanization, milk legislation, psychopathic offenders, and socialized medicine, among others.
The 1974 addition to the records of the Civic Club of Allegheny County is located in Boxes 28-44. Much of this addition relates to research and programs provided by the club as a service to Pittsburgh, but the addition also includes information about club history, committee activities, evaluations of legislation, and club members. A complete set of Voters' Directories published by the Civic Club has been removed from the collection and catalogued to provide greater access to their wealth of biographical information regarding local, state and national politicians; however, duplicates of most of these pamphlets may still be found within the collection. Other publications were maintained within the collection to provide background information on how issues, such as transit and anti-drug movements, among others, were handled outside of Allegheny County. Board of Directors meeting minutes and reports from 1895 to 1974 and photographs of Exceptionally Able Youth award ceremonies, Open Air Schools, Christmas tree lightings, and club members can be found within the addition. Films and audio tapes of various speeches and press conferences regarding topics such as the Golden Triangle and the North Side Stadium Project, among others, are also included.
Arrangement
The first series contains the records donated in 1970 and 1971. Series II through Series XIV contain materials donated in 1974.
Series I. Original 1970 and 1971 Donations
Series II. Civic Club History
Series III. Board of Directors Minutes
Series IV. Committees
Series V. Metropolitan Plan
Series VI. Home Rule
Series VII. Exceptionally Able Youth Program
Series VIII. Research and Subject Files
Series IX. Transit
Series X. Pollution
Series XI. Club Finances
Series XII. Voters' Directory
Series XIII. George W. Shankey, Jr.
Series XIV. Film and Audio Tapes
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Civic Club of Allegheny County on March 18, 1970, June 2, 1971, and in August 1974.
Previous Citation
Civic Club of Allegheny County Records, 1896-1974, AIS.1970.02, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Separated Material
Publications were removed from this collection and cataloged by the University Library System. Publications produced by the Civic Club include a complete set of the Voters' Directory pamphlets, as well as the newsletters The Civic Club Voice, News from the Civic Club of Allegheny County, Civic Bulletin for Pittsburgh and Allegheny County, The Monthly Bulletin, and Communicator, collectively ranging from 1914 to 1973. Other publications not produced by the club, but relating to their various research topics, have also been catalogued. Box 42 includes two 16 millimeter films and six one-quarter inch audio tapes which have been relocated to the Media Storage room.
Politics; Associations; Clubs -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Politicians -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County -- Biography; Election districts -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County -- Directories; Transportation; Brashear, John A. (John Alfred); Civic Club of Allegheny County (Pa.); Iams, Lucy Dorsey; Schuchman, F. E.; Shankey, George
- Original 1970 and 1971 Donations, 1898-1960; I.
  - Civic Club History, 1899-1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Civic Club Annual Meetings, 1896-1911 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Civic Club Annual Meetings, 1912-1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Affiliated Organization Activities, 1913-1945 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - All Nations Festival, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Allied Boards of Trade, 1913-1916, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Anti-Expectoration, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Arbor Day Hillside Planting, 1898-1928 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Arsenal Park, 1901-1907 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Art in Public Schools, 1898-1904 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "As Thousands Cheer" Political Rally, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Associated Charities, 1898-1912 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Associated Charities, 1913-1932 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Aviation, 1929, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Municipal Band, 1917-1923 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Billboards, 1903-1913 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Billboards, 1914-1922 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Billboards, 1926-1928 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Billboards, 1929-1935, 1940-1945, 1954-1958 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Block House (Point Park), 1902, 1905, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Blue Laws, 1929-1931 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Bridge Raising, 1908, 1915-1919, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Building Code Commission, 1910, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Child Labor, 1905-1923 (Box 3, Folder 24-25)
  - Child Welfare, 1897, 1913-1923 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Children's Service Bureau, 1909-1928 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Civic Art Commission, 1911-1917 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Civic Club—Program, 1933-1935 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Civic Club—Rummage Sale, 1932-1933 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Civic Club—Window Display, 1913-1922 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Civic Lectures Courses, 1909-1910 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Civic Club Ball, undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Comfort and Waiting Stations, 1913-1921 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Public Comfort Stations, 1912-1917 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Conservation, 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Conservation and Roadside Beauty, 1949-1960 (Box 4, Folder 36A)
  - Fire Protection, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Flood Control, 1910, 1936-1938 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Flower Shows, 1926-1932 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Stephen Collins Foster Anniversary Committee of the Civic Club, 1927-1938 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Stephen C. Foster Memorial, 1923-1926 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Stephen C. Foster Memorial (clippings), 1928-1930 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Stephen C. Foster Memorial (clippings), 1933-1954 (Box 5, Folder 43-50)
  - Stephen C. Foster Home (clippings), 1934-1936 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Death of Mrs. Marion Foster Welch's (daughter of Stephen C. Foster), 1935 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Stephen C. Foster, Miscellaneous (clippings), 1953 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Gardens, 1911-1917 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Health and Welfare (comfort stations, garbage, rats), 1944-1946 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Highways (Blvd. of the Allies, Liberty Tubes, Ohio River Blvd., Saw Mill), 1917-1940 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Municipal Hospital, 1937-1942 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Pittsburgh Housing, 1912-1919, 1939-1960 (Box 6, Folder 58-58C)
  - Immigration (clippings), 1916 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Jail Removal, 1925-1940, 1950, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Juvenile Court, 1901-1907 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Juvenile Court, 1905-1934 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Juvenile Court Scrapbook, 1899 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Libraries, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Legal Aid Society, 1899-1939 (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Legislative Program (state), 1932-1933 (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - Medical Inspection in Schools, 1905-1910 (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - National Conference of Charities and Corrections, Conventions (Cleveland and Pittsburgh), 1912, 1917 (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - Open Air Schools, 1909-1946 (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - Pittsburgh City Budget, 1908-1938, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - Pittsburgh City Charter, 1901 (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - Political Posters, 1931-1934, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - Social Security, 1945, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 73)
  - State Public Utilities Pay Raise, 1931 (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - "Manhattan Preferred", 1930 (Box 8, Folder 75)
  - "What's Up", 1931 (Box 8, Folder 76)
  - "Silver Domino", 1932 (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - "All to the Point", 1933 (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - "Hello Again", 1934 (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - Pittsburgh Playgrounds, 1899-1904 (Box 9, Volume 1)
  - Pittsburgh Playgrounds, 1905-1907 (Box 9, Volume 2)
  - Pittsburgh Playgrounds, 1908-1909 (Box 10, Volume 3)
  - Immigration, 1915-1916, 1919 (Box 10, Volume 4)
  - Juvenile Court, 1903-1905 (Box 11, Volume 5)
  - Civic Club History and Progress Reports, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Constitution and By-laws, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Officers, Board of Directors, and Committeemen, 1895-1959 (Box 12, Folder 03-04)
  - Membership Lists, 1916, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Founding Members, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1930-1954 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1949-1956 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - General Information, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Advisory Committee, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Better Housing Committee, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Child Welfare Committee, 1934 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - City and County Budget and Finance Committee, 1951-1956 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Constitutional Revision Committee, 1934-1935 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Education and School Study Committee, 1957-1958, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Exceptionally Able Youths Committee, 1947, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Education and School Study Committee, 1943-1944 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Flower Market Committee, 1929 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - General Information, undated (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Legislative Committee, 1945 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Legislative Committee, 1949, 1951 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Legislative Committee, 1957-1959 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Education Subcommittee, 1948-1949 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Labor Subcommittee, 1947, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Public Welfare Subcommittee, 1949, 1955, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Public Health Subcommittee, 1957, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Taxation Subcommittee, 1949, 1951 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Subcommittee on three Platoon Firemen's Bill, 1942 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Long Range Committee, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Meetings Committee, 1920 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Membership Committee, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Municipal Affairs Committee, 1946-1949 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Municipal Music Committee, 1923 (Box 13, Folder 32A)
  - Municipal Planning Committee, 1917 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Nominating Committee, 1930-1952 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Open Air School Committee, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Program Committee, 1944 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Publicity Committee, 1950 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Re-evaluation Committee, 1951-1954 (Box 13, Folder 38-39)
  - State Legislature Study Committee, 1951 (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - Thaw Memorial Committee, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - Voter's Directory Committee, 1946-1947, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - Miscellaneous, 1913, 1917, 1925-1969 (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - Tax Status, 1920-1960 (Box 13, Folder 44)
  - Memoranda, 1954-1959 (Box 13, Folder 45)
  - Annual Meeting Minutes, 1923-1964 (Box 14, Folder 46)
  - Annual Meeting Clippings, undate (Box 14, Folder 47)
  - Special Meetings, 1938, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 48)
  - Annual Meeting Reports, 1930-1957 (Box 14, Folder 49)
  - Annual Meeting News Releases, 1944-1959 (Box 14, Folder 50)
  - Membership Campaign, 1908-1967 (Box 14, Folder 51)
  - Legal Papers, undate (Box 14, Folder 52)
  - 25th Anniversary, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 53)
  - 30th Anniversary, 1925 (Box 14, Folder 54)
  - 50th Anniversary, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 55)
  - Health and Welfare Panel, 1955 (Box 14, Folder 56)
  - Housewarming, 1930 (Box 14, Folder 57)
  - Luncheons, 1910-1940 (Box 14, Folder 58)
  - Public Forums and Minutes, 1919 (Box 14, Folder 59)
  - Public Forums, 1919-1920 (Box 15, Folder 60)
  - Publicity, undate (Box 15, Folder 61)
  - Publications, undate (Box 15, Folder 62)
  - Legislative Bulletin, 1937-1953 (Box 15, Folder 63)
  - Miscellaneous, undate (Box 15, Folder 64)
  - A.B.C. Restaurant Ordinance, 1948, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 65)
  - ADA, Pittsburgh Chapter, undate (Box 15, Folder 66)
  - Air Pollution, 1957 (Box 15, Folder 67)
  - Allegheny Conference on Community Development, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 68)
  - Allegheny County Government, 1957, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 69)
  - Allegheny County Finances, 1954, 1957 (Box 15, Folder 70)
  - Allegheny County Health Study Commission, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 71)
  - Allegheny County Joint Committee on Scholarship Aid, 1957 (Box 15, Folder 72)
  - Allegheny County Sanitary Authority, 1946-1956 (Box 15, Folder 73)
  - Allegheny County Sunday-Rest Association, 1907 (Box 15, Folder 74)
  - American Association for Promoting Hygiene and Public Baths, 1917 (Box 15, Folder 75)
  - American Civic Association, 1908-1934 (Box 15, Folder 76)
  - Americanization (clippings), 1918 (Box 15, Folder 77)
  - Assessment Reform, 1922-1935 (Box 16, Folder 78)
  - Automobile Laws, 1956-1957 (Box 16, Folder 79)
  - Bridges, 1915-1916 (Box 16, Folder 80)
  - Building Code, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 81)
  - Bus Fare Protest, 1929 (Box 16, Folder 82)
  - Canalization of the Ohio River, 1929 (Box 16, Folder 83)
  - Carnegie Free Library of Allegheny, 1933 (Box 16, Folder 84)
  - Census, 1950 (Box 16, Folder 85)
  - Christmas Lighting and Decoration, 1926-1940 (Box 16, Folder 86)
  - Chronic Disease and Rehabilitation Center, 1946-1949 (Box 16, Folder 87)
  - City Manager, 1931-1939 (Box 16, Folder 88)
  - City Planning (clippings), 1917-1935, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 89)
  - Civic Muzzler Bill, undated (Box 16, Folder 90)
  - Civic Opera Site, 1949 (Box 16, Folder 91)
  - Code of Ethics, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 92)
  - Civil Service, 1921, 1946-1947 (Box 17, Folder 93)
  - Conemaugh Dam Project, 1947, 1950 (Box 17, Folder 94)
  - Constitutional Amendments (state), 1933, 1937 (Box 17, Folder 95)
  - Constitutional Revision (state), 1920-1936, 1953 (Box 17, Folder 96-97)
  - Co-operative School Study Committee, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 98)
  - County Fair Civic Club Distribution, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 99)
  - County Government, 1936, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 100)
  - Day Nursing Committee of Allegheny County, undated (Box 17, Folder 101)
  - Dirty Milk, 1939-1945 (Box 17, Folder 102)
  - Education, 1911-1944 (Box 17, Folder 103-107)
  - Education, 1946-1947 (Box 18, Folder 108)
  - Education, 1958-1960 (Box 18, Folder 109)
  - Fair Employment Practices, 1947-1948, 1958-1959 (Box 18, Folder 110)
  - Federal Aid to Education, 1948, 1956-1958 (Box 18, Folder 111)
  - Fee Offices, 1911-1935 (Box 18, Folder 112)
  - Flood Control (includes report about effects of the Flood of March 18, 1936), undated (Box 18, Folder 113)
  - Floods—Johnston, PA, 1899 (Box 18, Folder 114)
  - Foundations (Pittsburgh Foundation and Mellon Foundation), 1948-1949, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 115)
  - Garbage (rules and regulations), 1933-1934, 1952 (Box 18, Folder 116)
  - Home Rule, 1922-1958 (Box 18, Folder 117)
  - Junior Civic Club, 1922-1924 (Box 18, Folder 118)
  - Labor (clippings), 1958-1960 (Box 18, Folder 119)
  - Lake Building, 1948 (Box 18, Folder 120)
  - Lakes, Ponds, Dams, 1948-1950, 1956 (Box 18, Folder 121-122)
  - Land Use, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 123)
  - Land Use, 1955-1956 (Box 19, Folder 124-125)
  - Legislation (Federal) -- Highway Construction and Commercial Exploitation, 1956 (Box 19, Folder 126)
  - Legislation (State) -- General, 1913-1959 (Box 19, Folder 127-132)
  - Legislation (State) -- Increasing City's Borrowing Power, 1928 (Box 19, Folder 133)
  - Libraries—Allegheny County, PA, 1947-1959 (Box 19, Folder 134)
  - Light's Golden Jubilee, 1929 (Box 20, Folder 135)
  - Metropolitan Planning, 1920-1928 (Box 20, Folder 136)
  - Planning, 1929-1958 (Box 20, Folder 137)
  - Milk Legislation (clippings), 1939-1945, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 138)
  - Minor Judiciary, 1952 (Box 20, Folder 139)
  - Municipal Affairs (clippings), 1909-1959 (Box 20, Folder 140)
  - Municipal Lodging House, 1909-1910 (Box 20, Folder 141)
  - National Association of Housing Officials, 1935 (Box 20, Folder 142)
  - Noise and Noise Abatement, 1929, 1946-1950 (Box 20, Folder 143)
  - Pennsylvania Pitt's Partners, 1947 (Box 20, Folder 144-145)
  - Pennsylvania Economy League, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 146)
  - People's Baths, 1908, 1933 (Box 20, Folder 147)
  - Pittsburgh—Organizational Chart, 1919 (Box 20, Folder 148)
  - Pittsburgh Board of Public Education (clippings), 1958 (Box 20, Folder 149)
  - Pittsburgh Bureau of Fire, 1942, 1947, 1949 (Box 20, Folder 150)
  - Pittsburgh Bureau of Smoke Prevention, 1914, 1941-1955 (Box 20, Folder 151)
  - City Planning Commission, 1907-1912, 1951-1952 (Box 20, Folder 152)
  - Pittsburgh—Department of Public Welfare, 1934-1937, 1942 (Box 21, Folder 153)
  - Pittsburgh—Mayor's Commission for the Elimination of Smoke, 1941 (Box 21, Folder 154)
  - Pittsburgh Parking Authority, 1947-1953 (Box 21, Folder 155-156)
  - Pittsburgh—General, undated (Box 21, Folder 157)
  - Pittsburgh—Budget, 1934-1957 (Box 21, Folder 158-159)
  - Pittsburgh—Centennial, 1916 (Box 21, Folder 160)
  - Pittsburgh—Mayoral Election, 1929 (Box 21, Folder 161)
  - "The Pittsburgh Plan", 1913 (Box 21, Folder 162)
  - Psychopathic Offenders, 1949-1950 (Box 21, Folder 163)
  - Public Health and Welfare, 1955-1956 (Box 21, Folder 164)
  - Public Utilities, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 165)
  - Public Welfare, 1958-1959 (Box 21, Folder 166)
  - Power Strike, 1946 (Box 21, Folder 167)
  - Rackets (clippings), 1950 (Box 21, Folder 168)
  - Railways, 1918 (Box 21, Folder 169)
  - Reapportionment (clippings), 1941-1942 (Box 21, Folder 170)
  - School Feeding, 1933 (Box 21, Folder 171)
  - School Board, Elective, 1919 (Box 21, Folder 172)
  - School Budgets—Pittsburgh, 1958-1959 (Box 21, Folder 173-174)
  - School Extension (clippings), 1902, 1912-1918 (Box 21, Folder 175)
  - School Panel, Committee on Reorganization of Government in Allegheny County, 1955 (Box 21, Folder 176-177)
  - Schools—Pittsburgh, 1953 (Box 21, Folder 178)
  - Sewerage, 1952-1955 (Box 21, Folder 179)
  - Smoke Abatement Lectures (Notes of I.O. Arneson, Pittsburgh Coal Company), undated (Box 22, Folder 180)
  - The Smoke and Dust Abatement League, 1912, 1916 (Box 22, Folder 181)
  - Smoke and Smoke Control, 1940-1959 (Box 22, Folder 182-188)
  - Smoke and Smoke Control (clippings), 1941 (Box 22, Folder 189-190)
  - Smoke and Smoke Control (clippings), 1941-1959 (Box 23, Folder 191-198)
  - Social Centers (clippings), 1913-1916 (Box 23, Folder 199)
  - Socialized Medicine, 1943-1946 (Box 23, Folder 200)
  - Soho Public Baths History, undated (Box 24, Folder 201)
  - Soho Public Baths, 1908-1961 (Box 24, Folder 202)
  - Soho Public Baths Clippings, 1912-1943 (Box 24, Folder 203)
  - State Constitution Revision (Clippings), 1953 (Box 24, Folder 204)
  - Sterilization, 1913 (Box 24, Folder 205)
  - Stream Pollution, 1913-1959 (Box 24, Folder 206-210)
  - Taxation, 1947-1958 (Box 25, Folder 211)
  - Publications Regarding Taxation, 1946-1949, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 212)
  - Taxation Clippings, 1923-1959 (Box 25, Folder 213)
  - Town Hall, 1949 (Box 25, Folder 214)
  - Traffic, 1950, 1958-1959 (Box 25, Folder 215)
  - Traffic (Clippings), 1925-1927, 1946-1952 (Box 25, Folder 216)
  - Transit Authority, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 217)
  - United Smoke Control, 1942-1946 (Box 25, Folder 218-220)
  - United Smoke Control Publications, undated (Box 25, Folder 221)
  - Water Authority, 1951-1953 (Box 25, Folder 222)
  - Water Authority Clippings, 1952-1953 (Box 26, Folder 223)
  - Water Supply and Sewage Disposal, 1955-1958 (Box 26, Folder 224)
  - Waterfront Improvements, 1932-1936 (Box 26, Folder 225)
  - Women's Clubs, 1913-1915 (Box 26, Folder 226)
  - Women Labor, 1914, 1917 (Box 26, Folder 227)
  - Work Probe, 1950 (Box 26, Folder 228)
  - Zoning, 1949-1950, 1954, 1957 (Box 26, Folder 229)
  - Zoning Clippings, 1918-1959 (Box 26, Folder 230)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 26, Folder 231)
  - Brashear, John, 1940 (Box 26, Folder 232)
  - Brown, John P., undated (Box 26, Folder 233)
  - Christler, C.M., undated (Box 26, Folder 234)
  - Cunningham, Charles, undated (Box 26, Folder 235)
  - Dermitt, Miss William G., undated (Box 26, Folder 236)
  - Everstine, A. Perry, undated (Box 26, Folder 237)
  - Foster, Henry W., Jr., undated (Box 26, Folder 238)
  - Gray, James H., undated (Box 26, Folder 239)
  - Guthrie, Francis S., undated (Box 26, Folder 240)
  - Hailman, James D., undated (Box 26, Folder 241)
  - Hailman, Mrs. Johanna K.W., undated (Box 26, Folder 242)
  - Iams, Lucy Dorsey, undated (Box 26, Folder 243)
  - Kirchway, Dr. George W., undated (Box 26, Folder 244)
  - Knowles, Morris, undated (Box 26, Folder 245)
  - Lawrence, David L., 1958-1959 (Box 26, Folder 246)
  - Martin, Park H., undated (Box 26, Folder 247)
  - Lund, Harold C., undated (Box 27, Folder 248)
  - Mason, Lee F., undated (Box 27, Folder 249)
  - Munroe, D.D., undated (Box 27, Folder 250)
  - Munroe, Mrs. Grace Ralston, undated (Box 27, Folder 251)